Credits

Photo Credits

Chapter 1

Opener: © NASA/JPL/Space Science Institute; 1.1(leech): © St. Bartholomews Hospital/Science Source; 1.1(mushrooms): © IT Stock/age fotostock RF; 1.1(bacteria): © Science Source; 1.1(meerkats): © Jami Tarris/Getty Images; 1.1(sunflower): © Dave Thompson/Life File/Getty RF; 1.1(Giardia): © CDC/Dr. Stan Erlandsen; 1.3a: © Vol. 124/Corbis RF; 1.3b: © John Cancalosi/Getty Images; 1.4a(seedling): © Herman Eisenbeiss/Science Source; 1.4a(tree): © Photographer's Choice/Getty RF; 1.4b(egg): © David M.Phillips/Science Source; 1.4b(fetus): © Brand X Pictures/Punchstock RF; 1A: © Michael Freeman/Corbis RF; 1.6(paramecium): © M. I. Walker/Science Source; 1.6(mushrooms): © Ingram Publishing RF; 1.6(orchid): © Tinke Hamming/Ingram Publishing RF; 1.6(fox): © Corbis RF; 1.6(archaea): © Eye of Science/Science Source; 1.6(bacteria): © A.B. Dowsett/SPL/Science Source; 1.8(D. melanogaster): © Graphic Science/Alamy; 1.8(M. musculis): © Steve Gorton/Getty Images; 1.8(C. elegans): © Sinclair Stammers/Science Source; 1.8(A. thaliana): © Wildlife GmbH/Alamy; 1.9b(students, both): © image100 Ltd RF; 1.9d: © Phanie/Science Source; 1B(Dr. Marshall): © Tony McDonough/epa/Corbis; 1B(bacteria): © Eye of Science/Science Source; 1.11: © FLPA/Alamy.

Chapter 2

Opener: © Liquidlibrary/PictureQuest RF; 2.3a: © Biomed Commun./Custom Medical Stock Photo; 2.3b(patient): © National Institutes of Health; 2.3b(scan): © Mazzlota et al./Science Source; 2.4a: © Kim Scott/Ricochet Creative Productions LLC; 2.4b: © Mark Kostich/Getty RF; 2.5b(salt crystals): © Evelyn Jo Johnson; 2.5b(french fries): © PM Images/Getty RF; 2.8b: © Clerkenwell/Getty RF; 2.13: © Jeremy Burgess/SPL/Science Source; 2.14: © Don W. Fawcett/Science Source; 2.15: © Scimat/Science Source; 2.20b–c: © Purestock/Superstock RF; p. 36(woman): © Comstock/PunchStock RF; p. 36(blood cells): © P. Motta & S. Correr/Science Source; p. 36(man): © Suza Scalora/Getty RF.

Chapter 3

Opener: © Bruce Dale/National Geographic/Getty Images; 3.1(blood cells): © Prof. P. Motta, Dept. of Anatomy, Univ. LaSapienza Rome/SPL/Science Source; 3.1(nerve cells): © SPL/Science Source; 3.1(bone): © McGraw-Hill Education; 3.3a: © Ed Reschke/Getty Images; 3.3b: © Alfred Pasieka/Science Source; 3.3c: © Science Photo Library RF/Getty RF; 3Aa: © Frans Lanting/Mint Images/Getty Images; 3Ab: © Dr. Gopal Murti/Science Source; 3.4a: © Alfred Pasieka/Science Source; 3.9(all): © Dennis Kunkel/Phototake; 3.13(nuclear pores): © Don W. Fawcett/Science Source; 3.13(ER): © Martin M. Rotker/Science Source; 3.15(cilia): © Dr. G. Moscoso/Science Source, Inc.; 3.15(sperm): © David M. Phillips/Science Source; 3.20: © Keith R. Porter/Science Source; 3B: © C Squared Studios/Getty RF.

Chapter 4

Opener: © PHANIE/Science Source; 4.2(all), 4.5a: © Ed Reschke; 4.5b: © McGraw-Hill Education/Dennis Strete; 4.5c, 4.6, 4.8(all): © Ed Reschke; 4.10: © Eye of Science/Science Source, Inc.; 4.11a: © PhotoMix/Alamy; 4.11b: © James Stevenson/SPL/Science Source; 4B(Dinoire, both): © AFP/Getty Images; 4B(Nash, both): © AP Photo/Brigham and Women's Hospital; 4B: © Win McNamee/Getty Images News/Getty Images.

Chapter 5

Opener: © Adam Gault/Getty RF; 5.2(left): © Ed Reschke; 5.2(right): © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 5.3b: © McGraw-Hill Education/Professor David F. Cox; 5.4b: © Thomas Deerinck, NCMIR/Science Source; 5.5d: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 5.6b– c(both): © Ed Reschke; 5.6d: © Losevsky Pavel/Alamy RF; 5.7: © Image Source/Alamy RF; 5A: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 5.14a: © Pascal Goethgheluck/SPL/Science Source; 5.15: © SynCardia Systems, Inc.

Chapter 6

Openers: (main) © SPL/Science Source, (inset) © Andrew Syred/Science Source; 6.1: © Doug Menuez/Getty RF; 6.3a: © Andrew Syred/Science Source; 6.3c: © Ed Reschke/Getty Images; p. 119(sickled cells): © Phototake, Inc./Alamy; 6.7b: © Eye of Science/Science Source; 6A: © McGraw-Hill Education; 6B: © Keith Brofsky/Getty RF.

Chapter 7

Opener: © ISM/Phototake; 7.2a: © Ed Reschke/Photolibrary/Getty Images; 7.2b: © Ed Reschke/Getty Images; 7.2c: © Ed Reschke; 7.2d: © McGraw-Hill Education. Al Telser, photographer; 7.8b: © Dr. Arthur J. Olson, Scripps Institute; 7.11b: © Steve Gschmeissner/Science Source; 7.13a: © John Lund/Drew Kelly/Blend Images/Corbis RF; 7.13b: © Digital Vision/Getty RF; 7.13c: © Photodisc Collection/Getty RF; 7.14: © Southern Illinois University/Science Source.

Chapter 8

Opener: © Itsuo Inouye/AP Images; 8.1b: © Dr. David M. Phillips/Science Source; 8.1c: © Steve Gschmeissner/Science Source; 8.1d: © Dr. Gary D. Gaugler/Phototake; 8.2: © CNRI/SPL/Science Source; 8.4a: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 8.4b: © Cynthia Goldsmith/CDC; 8A: © KidStock/Getty RF; 8.10: © SPL/Science Source; 8.11: © ISM/Phototake; 8.14(camel): © Nils Kramer/Gertty RF; 8.14(bats): © Chris Howes/Wild Places Photography/Alamy; 8.16: © David McCarthy/Science Source.

Chapter 9

Opener: © Bubbles Photolibrary/Alamy; 9.5c: © Steve Gschmeissner/Getty RF; 9.6(villi): © Kage Mikrofotografie/Phototake; 9.6(microvilli): © Science Photo Library RF/Getty RF; 9B(all): © Given Imaging, a Covidien company. Used by permission. The use of any Covidien photo or image does not imply Covidient review or endorsement of any article or publication; p. 183(couple): © BananaStock/age fotostock RF; p. 183(scale): © Photodisc/Getty RF; p. 183(vegetables): © Photolink/Getty RF; 9.12: © Cole Group/Getty RF; 9.13: © Photodisc/Getty RF; 9C: © Evelyn Jo Johnson; 9.15: © USDA, ChooseMyPlate.gov website; 9.16a: © Ted Foxx/Alamy RF; 9.16b: © Donna Day/Stone/Getty Images; 9.16c: © Corbis RF; p. 193(ChooseMyPlate.gov): © USDA, ChooseMyPlate.gov website.

Chapter 10

Opener: © Image Source/Getty RF; 10.3: © Science Photo Library/Getty RF; 10.4: © CNRI/Phototake; 10.5(lower part): © Ed Reschke; 10.9: © Veronique Burger/Science Source; 10B: © Martina Paraninfi/Moment/Getty RF; 10.13a: © Matt Meadows/Getty Images; 10.13b: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source.

Chapter 11

Openers (left): © McGraw-Hill Education, (right): © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 11A: © AP Photo/Brian Walker; 11.3b: © James Cavallini/Science Source; 11.3c: © Ralph Hutchings/Visuals Unlimited/Corbis; 11.4(both): © Science Photo Library/Getty RF; 11.5a: © Joseph F. Gennaro Jr./Science Source; 11C: © Ian Hooton/Science Source; 11.11: © AJPhoto/Science Source.

Chapter 12

Opener: © Southern Stock Corp/Corbis; 12.1(hyaline, compact bone): © Ed Reschke; 12.1(osteocyte): © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 12.4b: © Corbis RF; 12A: © Michael Donne/Science Source; 12.9a: © Gerard Vandystadt/Science Source; 12Ba–b: © Scott Camazine/Science Source; 12C(left): © Corbis RF; 12Ca: © Susumu Nishinaga/Science Source; 12Cb: © Ed Reschke/Photolibrary/Getty Images; 12C(right): © Bill Aaron/PhotoEdit; 12.14b: © Tony Freeman/PhotoEdit.

Chapter 13

Opener: © Erproductions Ltd/Blend Images/Corbis; 13.1a: © Ed Reschke; 13.1b: © McGraw-Hill Education/Dennis Strete; 13.1c: © Ed Reschke; 13.4(both): © McGraw-Hill Education. J.W. Ramsey, photographer; 13.6(gymnast): © Corbis RF; 13.6(muscle): © Biology Media/Science Source; 13.7: © Ed Reschke/Oxford Scientific/Getty Images; 13A: © Thinkstock/Getty RF; 13B: © Justin Sullivan/Getty Images; 13.12(left): © Lawrence Manning/Corbis; 13.12(center): © Dr. Gladden Willis/Visuals Unlimited/Corbis; 13.12(right): © Corbis RF; 13A(boys): © ImageState/PunchStock RF; 13A(teens): © Nancy Ney/Photodisc/Getty RF; 13A(cyclists): © Getty Images/Stockbyte RF; 13C: © Focus on Sport/Getty Images.

Chapter 14

Opener: © Peter Duddek/Visum/The Image Works; 14.2a: © McGraw-Hill Education/Dr. Dennis Emery/Dept. of Zoology and Genetics, Iowa State University; 14.2c: © David M. Phillips/Science Source; 14.5a: © Science Source; 14Aa: Drawing is from "Histologie due Systeme Nerveux de l'Homme et des Vertebres. © Instituto Cajal, Madrid, Spain; 14Ab: © David Becker/Science Source; 14.7a: © Karl E. Deckart/Phototake; 14.7d: © McGraw-Hill Education/Rebecca Gray, photographer & Don Kincaid, dissections; 14.8b: © Colin Chumbley/Science Source/Science Source; 14.13(all): © Marcus Raichle; 14.14: © PASIEKA/Science Photo Library/Science Source; 14.18(both): © Science Source.

Chapter 15

Openers (both): © AP Images/Gene J. Puskar; 15.4b(both): © Omikron/SPL/Science Source; 15.8a: © Science Source; 15.9b: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 15A: © Pascal Goetgheluck/Science Source; 15.13: © P. Motta/SPL/Science Source; 15B(both): © Dr. Yeohash Raphael, the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.

Chapter 16

Opener: © AP Photo/Evansville Courier & Press, Brien Vincent; 16.8: © Associated Press/Ibrahim Usta; 16.9(hands): © Bart's Medical Library/Phototake; 16.9(man): © Yasser Al-Zayyat/AFP/Getty Images; 16.10a: © Bruce Coleman, Inc./Alamy; 16.10b: © Medical-on-Line/Alamy; 16.10c: © Dr. P. Marazzi/Science Source; 16.15a: © Custom Medical Stock Photo; 16.15b: © NMSB/Custom Medical Stock Photo; 16.16(both): © Shannon Halverson; 16.17: © Peter Arnold, Inc./Alamy; 16.18(both): © Victor P. Eroschenko; 16A: © McGraw-Hill Education; 16.21: © Evelyn Jo Johnson.

Chapter 17

Opener: © UpperCut Images/Getty RF; 17.3b: © Anatomical Travelogue/Science Source; 17.4b: © Ed Reschke; 17A: © Getty Images; 17.8: © Ed Reschke; 17.14a: © Saturn Stills/Science Source; 17.14b: © Keith Brofsky/Getty RF; 17.14c: © McGraw-Hill Education/John Thoeming; 17B: © Nancy R. Cohen/Getty RF; 17.16: © CC Studio/SPL/Science Source; 17.17: © Dr. Olivier Schwartz/Institut Pasteur/Science Source; 17.18a: © Bart's Medical Library/Phototake; 17.18b: © Biophoto Associates/Science Source; 17.18c: © Dennis Kunkel Microscopy, Inc./Visuals Unlimited/Corbis; 17.19: © Biomedical Imaging Unit, Southampton General Hospital/Science Source; 17C(left): © Corbis RF; 17C(right): © David Raymer/Corbis; 17D(drug user): © Brand X Pictures RF; 17.20: © Melba Photo Agency/Alamy RF.

Chapter 18

Opener: © John Slater/Getty RF; 18.1: © David M. Phillips/Science Source; 18.2(fertilization): © Don W. Fawcett/Science Source; 18.2(2-cell stage): © Rawlins PhD/Getty Images; 18.2(morula): © RBM Online/epa/Corbis; 18.2(implantation): © Bettmann/Corbis; 18.6a: © Anatomical Travelogue/Science Source; 18.8: © James Stevenson/Science Source; 18.11: © Dr. Howard Jones, Eastern VA Medical School; 18.13c: © Rune Hellestad/Corbis; 18.14: © Image Source/Getty RF; 18.15: © Ronnie Kaufman/Corbis.

Chapter 19

Opener: © Kevin Mazur/Contributor/WireImage/Getty Images; 19.1: © CNRI/SPL/Science Source; 19.5(top): © Scott Camazine/Science Source; 19.5(bottom): © Edward Kinsman/Science Source; 19.8(prophase, early prophase, metaphase, anaphase, telophase): © Ed Reschke; 19.8(prometaphase): © Michael Abbey/Science Source; 19.16a: © Scott Wintrow/Getty Images; 19.16b: © CNRI/SPL/Science Source; 19.19b: © The Williams Syndrome Association; 19.20b: © Wellcome Image Library/Custom Medical Stock Photo.

Chapter 20

Opener: © Strauss/Curtis/Corbis; 20.1a: © Biology Media/Science Source; 20.1b: © SPL/Science Source; 20.1c: © Martin M. Rotker/Science Source; 20.8A: © Custom Medical Stock Photo; 20.8B: © ISM/Phototake; 20.8C: © Dr. P. Marazzi/Science Source; 20.8D: © Custom Medical Stock Photo; 20.8E: © BSIP/Universal Images Group/Getty Images; 20.9(both): © UHB Trust/Getty Images; 20.10: © BSIP/Phototake; 20.11: © Simon Fraser/Royal Victoria Infirmary/Science Source; 20D: © Obstetrics & Gynaecology/SPL/Science Source; 20E: © Visuals Unlimited/Corbis.

Chapter 21

Opener: © Don Tremain/Getty RF; 21.2a(both): © McGraw-Hill Education/Bob Coyle; 21.2c: © Image Source/PunchStock RF; 21.2d: © Creatas/PunchStock RF; 21.12(both): © Dr. Hemachandra Reddy, The Neurological Science Institute, Oregon Health & Science University; 21A(both): © Brand X/SuperStock RF; 21.13: © University of Connecticut/Peter Morenus, photographer; 21.15: © Jane Burton/Photoshot; 21.16: © Ed Reschke; 21.17: © Medical-On-Line/Alamy; 21.21(both): © Dr. Rabi Tawil, Director, Neuromuscular Pathology Laboratory, University of Rochester Medical Center; 21.21(boy): © Muscular Dystrophy Association.

Chapter 22

Opener: © Mark Hatfield/Getty RF; 22A(both): © Science Source; 22.11: © Science Source; 22.14a: © Lawrence Berkeley National Lab/Roy Kaltschmidt, photographer; 22.18a: © Maximilian Stock Ltd./Science Source; 22.18b: © Robert H. Devlin, Fisheries and Oceans Canada; 22.18c: © Joerg Boething/Alamy; 22.18d: © Jerry Mason/Science Source; 22.19a(all): © Monsanto; 22.20(both): © Eduardo Blumwald; 22.22a–c(chimp): © Digital Vision/Getty RF; 22.22a, c(human): © Getty RF; 22.22b(human): © McGraw-Hill Education/Bob Coyle; 22C: © Deco/Alamy RF.

Chapter 23

Opener: © Frank Vinken/Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology, Leipzig, Germany; 23.5(fossil): © Jean-Claude Carton/PhotoShot; 23.5(artist depiction): © Interstellar Illustrations/Joe Tucciarone; 23.7(sugar glider): © ANT Photo Library/Science Source; 23.7(wombat): © Photodisc Blue/Getty RF; 23.7(kangaroo): © George Holton/Science Source; 23.9(both): © Carolina Biological Supply/Phototake; 23.12(gibbon): © Getty RF; 23.12(orangutan, chimps, gorillas): © Creatas/PunchStock RF; 23.15a: © Dan Dreyfus and Associates; 23.15b: © John Reader/Science Source; 23.16(A. ramidus): © Richard T. Nowitz/Science Source; 23.16(A. afarensis): © Scott Camazine/Alamy; 23.16(A. africanus): © Philippe Plailly/Science Source; 23.16(H. habilis): © Kike Calvo VWPics/Superstock; 23.16(H. sapiens): © Kenneth Garrett/Getty Images; 23Aa: © Peter Schouten/National Geographic Society/Reuters/Corbis; 23Ab: © AP Photo/Richard Lewis; 23.17: © Associated Press; 23.20: © Tomas Abad/agefotostock/SuperStock; 23.21a: © PhotoDisc/Getty RF; 23.21b: © Sylvia S. Mader; 23.21c: © Sue Flood/Stone/Getty Images; 23B: © Peter Bowater/Science Source.

Chapter 24

Opener: © DLILLC/Corbis RF; 24.1(taiga): © John E. Marriott/All Canada Photos/Getty Images; 24.1(temperate deciduous forest): © David Sucsy/E+/Getty RF; 24.1(tropical rain forest): © Digital Vision/Getty RF; 24.1(tundra): © Alan Majchrowicz/Photolibrary/Getty RF; 24.2a: © Francois Gohier/Science Source; 24.2b: © McGraw-Hill Education/Carlyn Iverson; 24.2c: © David Hall/Science Source; 24.2d: © Corbis RF; 24.3a(diatom): © Ed Reschke; 24.3a(tree): © Authors Image/PunchStock RF; 24.3b(caterpillar): © Corbis RF; 24.3b(rabbit): © Gerald C. Kelley/Science Source; 24.3c(snake eating rabbit): © Derrick Hamrick/imagebroker/Corbis; 24.3c(hawk carrying snake): © Tze-hsin Woo/Getty RF; 24.3d(bacteria): © Image Source/Getty RF; 24.3d(mushroom): © Denise McCullough; 24Aa: © Brian J. Skerry/Getty Images; 24Ab: © Jose Luis Pelaez Inc./Blend Images LLC RF; 24.5: © George D. Lepp/Science Source; 24B(left): © igor kisselev, www.close-up.biz/Getty RF; 24B(right): © Howard Davies/Corbis; 24.11b: © Russell Millner/Alamy; 24.13a: © Larry Lee Photography/Corbis RF; 24.13b: © Oxford Scientific/Photolibrary/Getty Images; 24.13c: © Sue Baker/Science Source.

Chapter 25

Opener: © J. Emilio Flores/La Opinion/Newscom; 25.2c: © Tim Graham/Getty Images; 25.3(land): © G369PhotoDisc/Getty RF; 25.3(water): © Evelyn Jo Johnson; 25.3(food): © McGraw-Hill Education/John Thoeming; 25.3(energy): © Photo Link/Getty RF; 25.3(minerals): © T. O'Keefe/PhotoLink/Getty RF; 25.4b: © Mark Gibson/Getty Images; 25.5b: © Carlos Dominguez/Science Source; 25.6b: © L. Hobbs/PhotoLink/Getty RF; 25.7a: © Comstock Images/Alamy RF; 25.7b: © David Birkbeck/Getty RF; 25.7c: © Stockbyte/PunchStock RF; 25.8: © AP Photo/Mark Gormus; 25.9a: © Bruno Barbier/Getty Images; 25.9b: © Milan Stojanovic/Getty RF; 25.9c: © View Stock/Alamy; 25.10a: © David R. Frazier/Science Source; 25.10b: © Inga Spence/Alamy; 25.10c: © Perennou Nuridsany/Science Source; 25.11: © USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service/Tim McCabe; 25Aa: © USDA/Doug Wilson, photographer; 25Ab: © Norm Thomas/Science Source; 25Ac: © Pixtal/Age fotostock RF; 25.12a: © Corbis RF; 25.12b: © Glen Allison/Getty RF; 25.12c: © Danita Delimont/Getty Images; 25.12d: © Photo Link/Getty RF; 25.13a: © LusoEnvironment/Alamy; 25.13b: © Piroschka van de Wouw/EPA/Newscom; 25.15b: © IT Stock/PunchStock RF; 25.16a: © Kevin Fleming/Corbis; 25.16b–c(both): © Peter Auster/University of Connecticut; 25.17(periwinkle): © Steven P. Lynch; 25.17(armadillo): © PhotoDisc/Getty RF; 25.17(boat): © Tim Laman/Getty RF; 25.17(bat): © Dr. Merlin D. Tuttle/Science Source; 25.17(ladybug): © Martin Ruegner/Masterfile RF; 25.17(rubber tree): © Bryn Campbell/Stone/Getty Images; 25B: © USDA/Lila De Guzman, photographer; 25C(jaguar): © Photodisc RF; 25C(turtle): © hotshotsworldwide/Getty RF; 25.18(deforestation): © Carlos Dominguez/Science Source; 25.18(overfishing): © Kevin Fleming/Corbis; 25.18(waste accumulation): © McGraw-Hill Education/Pat Watson; 25.18(erosion): © USDA/Nature Source/Science Source; 25.18(habitat loss): © Bill Zimmer/Associated Press; 25.18(air pollution): © Larry Lee Photography/Corbis RF; 25.19(farming): © Inga Spence/Alamy; 25.19(wetland preservation): © Peter DeJong/Associated Press; 25.19(recycling): © Jeffrey Greenberg/Science Source; 25.19(pest management): © Perennou Nuridsany/Science Source; 25.19(temperature control): © Reuters/Corbis; 25.19(mass transit): © LusoEnvironment/Alamy; 25.20: © Photo by Erwin Cole, USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service; 25.21: © Diane Cook and Len Jenshel/Getty Images; p. 576(land): © PhotoDisc/Getty RF; p. 576(water): © Evelyn Jo Johnson; p. 576(food): © McGraw-Hill Education/John Thoeming; p. 576(energy): © Photo Link/Getty RF; p. 576(minerals): © T. O'Keefe/PhotoLink/Getty RF.